Hey everyone once again welcome to w kaptech my
self Gaurav and through this particular video of today
we are going to understand
how we can read out any image and
how we can show it, that means if you have
an image here in a particular
folder and if you want to see it then
basically you
can see it like this there is a folder inside this folder
if I talk about images then see
we have this image something like this so what am
I doing with this image I can
see it easily here and I can
move it like this I can see it easily here
and I can also run it
if we can do all these things here
pythonanywhere.com
let's see it here so
for that I will take you to
import python2 module
I will use cv2 through cv2 you
can use open cv now
what do you have inside this first of all the image is
read out that means which
image do you want to see  What do you do with that image? You
read it out. Now
what do you have to read the image?
Inside this, you have a function called
I am read function, with the help of which
your image is
read out here. Now, when we call this function,
we need
a variable for that. So, first of all, I will
create a variable here with the name of I ams. And then
next, here inside cv2, what do you have,
I am read function,
through which you will have your
file, it will be read here. Now, if we
talk about the image here, then what are the names of the images here?
Image one, Image two, Image three,
Image four, we have given the names like this. So, I am going to
give the name of this image directly
because the
python.py file that I am
giving, this image of mine has been
read here. Now what will happen next?
Here, what do we want to do with the image? We
want to show it. Showing means
we want to show the image. Basically, to
show the image, there is a function called I am show.  What does this do for
you, it shows the
image here. Look,
what does this IM read do? The image that you have, the
file of that image, the path from
where we have to bring our image,
what does it do? It reads that image here. Then let's
talk about the second here, so now
we have to show the image here, I have to
show it here, so for that I have
cv2 or cv2 dot here.
What do you have here, there is a show function, with the help of which function
what do we do, we
show our image. Now what does this IM image show
function do for you, it
creates a block for you, that means it
creates a window for you, inside which your
image is displayed here. As
I tell you, doing it practically here,
this is my image, if I double click on this image, then
this window opens. If
I make it small, then this window
opens inside which our
image is displayed here. Now what happens in this,
first of all, the
name of the image is written on top of your image.  It is written that we
can also give the name of the window here and the second
thing here is that your image is
visible inside it, so we are
also going to do something like this, so this
IM show that you have, here
you will have two parameters inside it, in which the
first parameter will be
what do you want to name that window, so
I would like to name the window here as Lay
Cube, so I named the window here as
W Cube Take then next now
I have to
give the name of the image that I want to show, that means the
variable that we have defined for that image will have to be
given, so here
I have defined a variable in the name of IMG, I have
given it here, what does it do to your
images here, that means if you have more than one
image, then what does it do here, it works to show all the images, otherwise
otherwise your single image will
show here, now after this
what do we want to do with our image window, we want to wait,
if I just run it, then run
What will happen to you as soon as you do this, it will run and
you will not know anything, that
means the looping system that runs inside it
runs for less than a millisecond, then if you
want to stop that image, then for that you need the
wait key. What do you do with the help of the wait key?
What do you do with your window? You stop it here. So
now let's talk about how to apply the wait key. For that
you need
cv2 here, the wait key and
what does the use of the wait key do?
Your frame means your window is
used to hold it.
Now inside this you go to the
timing, for how much time should your
window be held, so you
give that time. The time given inside it is
given in a millisecond, like if I put one here, it will work
here for 1 millisecond, it will
work for 2 milliseconds, it will
work for 3 milliseconds, but
inside this wait key there is one more thing here that
inside this wait key  If you pass zero
then what happens to you is that when
you press any key on your keyboard,
then
that window
closes. Under this wait key, you
can give many different numbers here, on which
your wait key will work. So first of all
I will talk about
what will be done under this wait key. So
under the wait key, if I want to make an
image wait for 5 seconds or make an
image work for one second, then
I will convert it from milliseconds to seconds,
for that I am going to write 1000 here. What will this wait key do to
your
image, what will it do here, it will stop it and
keep it, so I will write it here
that if you have a frame of your image,
yes the frame of the image that you have here,
what does it do to the frame of the image, it makes it wait here,
now the time that burns inside this,
what does that time run, here you have
MS  That means the time runs in milliseconds
and along with that if you
pass zero here and what did you do,
what did you do if you pass zero here
then what does it do that your keyboard
here, whenever you
press any key here, what will it do for you, it will
work here, that means it will
close it, now this thing that you have,
your image will open and after
being an image it will stay with you for some time,
after that your window should
close automatically, that means it should
close after milliseconds or if
you want that your
window here, that window should close when you press any button, then
you will have to close that window,
for that you get cv2 here, here your
destroy window goes, now
here inside destroy window you have
two functions working, one is destroy
all windows, here after a second
what do you have, cv2 dot here is
destroy window and see
what is the difference between both, I will show you both  Let me
tell you things, I will explain everything here that
see cv2
uses destroy all windows, cv2
uses destroy all windows, so
in this case, whatever number
of windows you have open, right now
what have we done, we will open only one window,
that is, we will open only one frame which will be
related to image one, if you have
multiple such windows open, then
what happens inside that case is that you can
close those multiple windows,
press one key simultaneously, then what happens here,
all the windows get closed, yes I will
write here that all the windows that you have
here, what happens, all the windows
you have here, get closed here and
next, if we talk about destroy window, then what does
destroy window do that
any number of
window that you give here, what will it do to you, it will close that window only, that
means what will it
do, only what will it do to you which is
one window here, yes only if I talk about one window
here, it will close only that one  What will
you do, you are going to close it, so
here you have two windows,
what do you do, close the window,
so if you want to show an image
inside a frame through C2,
then first of all you have to read out the image,
then you have to show the image, to show the
image means you have to create a frame
here, inside which our
image comes here, then
after that for how many seconds you have to keep it stopped,
you have to close it,
then you have to close all the windows,
let's run it and
see how it works here, then
as soon as you run it, see,
a window came below you and it also went away, it
came for some time, means it came for a second
and went away, we did not know the time, so
I increase its time a little,
here by increasing the end time, I make this time for
10 seconds here
and as soon as I run it, see, a window came to
you, inside which my image is
visible here, and after 10
seconds it automatically  What will happen, the window will
close, I did
not need to close it here, what has happened here, it has
closed automatically, so here the
time is given here, on which
you have to close the window here,
if you want that your
window should remain open and when you
press any key, only then that window should close, then
here you have to pass
zero, what do you do here,
pass zero, as soon as you pass zero,
what will you have with your window,
after pressing any particular key, what will you have with your
window, the window will close, let's run it
here, so see, my window has
opened here, now it will
never close until I
press any key on the keyboard, so right now
I do one thing, I press this cap key, so as soon as I press the escape key, my window has
closed automatically and my image is
visible here, now here
destroy all windows means that
all the windows that you are opening here,
all those windows will be closed  It will
close here, now see
how different windows can be opened here, it
means here we have opened only a single
window and by opening a single window
we have seen some things here, so
what do we do here, let's
see the multiple windows,
how multiple windows work here, so
I am taking it here again and
this is mine, okay, so let's
create multiple windows here and
after multiple windows, let's see
how multiple windows are and in
this way you can close and use multiple windows, so
like
what I did here, we have a window here
and have applied the destroy key, wait key etc.
I do one thing, create another window
here and just run it, here
I have created another window here by the name of WS Captek One and
as soon as
I run it, see, I have
two windows together, see here
one window is this, the second window is here,
inside which you will see two different images here
And as soon as I
press the escape key, both the windows are
closing together here. See, if I am running
here, both the windows are coming, the
name of one of them is Cube Tech
here and the name of the other one is Cube Tech One. The
name here is Cube Tech One. So
you have these two windows, inside which you can
see two different images here. So
right now, if I press one button, all the
windows will close here. So
what happened here because of destroy all
windows, this happened here. If I turn
off destroy all windows here
and use destroy windows here, then the particular window that I will
name inside the destroy window,
that particular window will
close. Then see here, I have
given the name of the window that I want to
destroy here. So,
I have written the name here that Cube
Tech One. What do I have to do here, I have to close that one.
See, I
will run here, so look at me.  W Captek is
also coming to you, W Captek is also coming
and as soon as I come towards the scape, the
La Cube Tech one closes and the one
which is by the name of La Cube Tech is
still open with me here, if
I want, I can close it by closing it from here,
so now do not close it by closing it here
because what it does is that it can
create a problem inside your system, so that's why
you should never close it from here, so
what can you do in this way, you can
close your particular window here, so the destroy
window function which you have does a different work and
what does the destroy all windows function do here, it does different work, so
what did we see here now that how can you
show an image
and how can you get an image
read here and here
we saw the difference between destroy all window and destroy window that how
these two
work here.  So that is all for
today's video,
in which we
learned how to read out any image and
how we can show that image, how we can show it on top of a window,
we understood this through this particular video today, so that is all for
today's video, see
you in our next video, until then stay with us like this till then
goodbye
[Music]
Hey